When working with data you'll most likely use databases from many sources.
处理数据时 你很可能要用不同来源的数据库
Pandas allows us to load databases of different formats into DataFrames.
Pandas 允许我们把不同格式的数据库加载到 DataFrame 中
One of the most popular formats used to store data is CSV or comma separated values.
最常见的数据存储格式是 CSV 也即逗号分隔型取值格式
We can load CSV files into DataFrames using the read CSV function.
我们可以用函数 read_csv 把 CSV 文件加载到 DataFrame 中
Let's load Google stock data into a DataFrame.
我们来把谷歌股票数据加载到 DataFrame 中
This file was taken from Yahoo finances and contains Google stock data from August 19th,
该文件源自雅虎财经 包含了 2004 年 8 月 19 日
2004 to October 13th, 2017.
到 2017 年 10 月 13 日的谷歌股票数据
The DataFrame consists of 3,313 rows and seven columns.
这个 DataFrame 有 3313 行 7 列
Let's look at the stock data.
我们来看里面的股票数据
We can see it's a pretty large dataset and that Pandas
这是个相当大的数据集
automatically assign numerical row indices to the DataFrame.
Pandas 自动给 DataFrame 添加了数字行索引
Pandas also use the names that appeared in the CSV file to assign the column labels.
并用 CSV 文件里的名称来给列标签赋值
When dealing with large data sets like this one,
处理像这样的大数据集时
it's often useful to just take a look at
不要一头扎进数据集里
the first few rows of data instead of the whole dataset.
先看看前几行数据会很有帮助
We can take a look at the first five rows using the head method.
我们可以用方法 head 来观察前五行
We can also take a look at the last five rows of data using the tail method.
也可以用方法 tail 来观察最后五行数据
Both of these accept an integer as an argument
这两个方法都接受一个整数参数
if you want to specify a different number of rows to return.
方便你指定要返回的行数
For example, I can get the last eight rows like this,
比如 我可以像这样访问最后八行
or the first two rows like this.
或像这样访问前两行
Let's do a quick check to see whether we have any none values in this data set.
我们快速检查一下数据集里是否有 NaN 值
To do so, we will use the "Is no" method followed by
为此 我们可以依次调用方法 isnull 和 any
the "Any" method to check whether any of the columns contain none values.
检查有没有哪一列具有 NaN 值
This shows us that we have no missing data.
从这里可以看出 没有缺失数据
When dealing with large data sets,
在处理大数据集时
it's often useful to get statistical information from them.
先获取数据集的统计信息会很有帮助
Pandas provides a described method which returns
Pandas 提供的方法 descirbe
descriptive statistics on each column of the DataFrame.
可以返回 DataFrame 各列的描述性统计数据
If desired, we can apply the describe method on a single column like this.
需要的话 我们也可以像这样只对一列应用方法 describe
Similarly, you can also look at one statistic by
同理 你也可以用 Pandas 提供的各种统计函数
using one of the many statistical functions that Pandas provides.
查看任一种统计数据
Here are some examples.
我们来看些例子
This gives us the maximum value in each column,
这里给出了各列的最大值
and this gives us the mean of each column,
这里给出了各列的平均值
and this gives us the minimum value in a specific column.
这里给出了某一列的最小值
Another important statistical measure is data correlation.
还有一项重要的统计数据 即数据相关性
We can use the core method to get the correlation between different columns.
我们可以用方法 corr 来获取各列的相关性
Lastly, let's look at the group by method,
最后 我们来看看方法 groupby
which allows us to group data to get different types of information.
该方法可以分组数据 从而提炼出多种信息
For the following examples,
接下来
we are going to load data about a fake company.
我们要加载一个虚构公司的数据
This data contains information for the years 1990 through 1992.
数据包含了公司 1990 到 1992 年的信息
And for each year, we see the name of the employees,
每一年都记录着员工姓名、
the department they worked for,
员工所在部门、
their age, and their annual salary.
员工年龄以及年薪
Now, let's use the group by method to get information.
现在我们用方法 groupby 来提炼一些信息
Let's calculate how much money the company spent on salaries each year.
我们来计算公司每年的薪资支出
To do this, we will group the data by year and then add
为此 我们可以按年份对数据进行分组
up the salaries of all of the employees with the sum method.
然后用方法 sum 把所有员工的薪资加起来
The company spent a total of $150,000 in 1990,
该公司 1990 年的薪资支出为 15 万美元
$162,000 in 1991, and $174,000 in 1992.
1991 年的支出为 16.2 万美元 1992 年的支出为 17.4 万美元
If we want to know the average salary for each year,
如果想知道每年的平均薪资
we can repeat the last step replacing the sum method with the mean method.
可以把上一步的方法 sum 改成 mean
Now, let's see how much in total each employee got paid during those five years.
现在我们来研究各员工五年的总薪资
In this case, we will group the data by name and then add up the salaries for each year.
为此 我们可以按姓名对数据进行分组 然后把各年的薪资加起来
Now let's see what the salary distribution per department was per year.
现在我们来看各部门每年的薪资分布
In this case, we will group the data by year and
为此 我们可以按年份和部门对数据进行分组
by department and then add up the salaries for each group.
然后统计各组的薪资总和
We can see that in 1990,
我们可以看到
the Admin department paid $55,000 in salaries,
1990 年 行政部薪资支出为 5.5 万美元
HR $50,000 and R and D, $48,000.
人力资源部的支出为 5 万美元 研发部的支出为 4.8 万美元
And in 1992 the admin department paid $122,000 in salaries, and so on.
1992 年 行政部的薪资支出为 12.2 万美元 以此类推